AMJAD SEYEDI **Graduate Research Assistant**

amjadseyedi.github.io github.com/AmjadSeyedi

+98 936 672 1167 @ amjadseyedi@uok.ac.ir

Representation Learning Lab (222), Computer Engineering Department, Engineering Faculty, University of Kurdistan, Sanandaj, Iran



BRIEFLY

As a graduate research assistant at the University of Kurdistan, I work on representation learning with a focus on robustness and generalization. I also lead the Algebraic Machine Learning Team (AML team), a group that explores fundamental methods in unsupervised machine learning and representation theory. I have a Master's degree in Artificial Intelligence from the same university, where I worked with Dr. Parham Moradi and Dr. Fardin Akhlaghian on matrix factorization and low-rank approximation for various applications such as semi-supervised learning, recommendation systems, and multi-label classification. I also have an Associate and a Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering.

RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Machine learning, Representation learning, Numerical Linear Algebra
- Generalization, Low-rank approximation, Adversarial training
- Deep Learning, Self-supervised/Semi-supervised learning
- Robustness, Fairness, Interpretability, Explainability



EDUCATION

Master

Artificial Intelligence, University of Kurdistan, Sanandaj, Iran, (Sep 2015 – Feb 2018)

- > Thesis title: A Graph-based Semi-Supervised Learning Approach for Multi-Label Classification.
- > Advisors: Dr. Parham Moradi and Dr. Fardin Akhlaghian.
- > Courses: machine learning, statistical pattern recognition, neural networks, advanced artificial intelligence, computer vision, digital image processing, distributed systems, and fuzzy sets & systems.

Bachelor

Sofware Engineering, AMIRKABIR TECHNICAL COLLEGE, ARAK, IRAN, (Jan 2012 - Jun 2014)

> Project title: Manufacturing and Setting up a Video Conferencing Software.

Associate

Computer Software, TABRIZ TECHNICAL COLLEGE, TABRIZ, IRAN, (Jan 2009 – Jun 2011)

> Supplementary courses in computer science and software engineering.

TechSchool | Computer, Taleghani High School, Sanandaj, Iran, (Sep 2005 - Jun 2007)

> A two-year education in basic computer science



EXPERIENCE

Thesis Advisor

Artificial Intelligence (graduate), UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, SANANDAJ, IRAN, (Sep 2020 - Present)

- > eight students have graduated. I am currently advising four master's students.
- > Topics: representation learning, deep learning, matrix factorization, semi-supervised learning, selfsupervised learning, robust learning, and sparse coding.
- > problems: data representation, data clustering, graph clustering, recommendation systems, link prediction, and feature selection.

Research Assist.

Representation Learning, University of Kurdistan, Sanandaj, Iran, (Sep 2019 - Present)

- > Topics: matrix factorization, distributionally robust learning, generalization, and adversarial training
- > applications: image inpainting and recommendation systems.

Teaching Assist.

Artificial Intelligence (graduate), UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, (Jan 2019 - Present)

- > Advanced Concepts in Artificial Intelligence (Graduate), Spring 2023, Fall 2023
- > Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Machine Learning (Graduate), Fall 2022
- > Pattern Recognition (Graduate), Spring 2019 Spring 2023
- > Special Topics in Artificial Intelligence (Graduate), Fall 2021
- > lectures: Semi-supervised learning, Modern Machine Learning Paradigms, Nonnegative matrix factorizations, Transformer Networks

Lab Instructor

Computer Lab (undergraduate), UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, SANANDAJ, IRAN, (Fall 2019)

> I had two 14-person classes on computer basics.

AMJAD SEYEDI 1



Under-Review

A Bi-level Deep Human Action Representation based on the Sequence of Action Segments

F. Akhlaghian, M. Ramezani, H. Afshoon, **S. A. Seyedi**, and A. Moradiani *Neural Computing and Applications* [3rd Revision], November 2023.

Towards Cohesion-Fairness Harmony: Contrastive Regularization in Individual Fair Graph Clustering S. Ghodsi, S. A. Seyedi, and E. Ntoutsi.

Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (PAKDD), 2024 [Accepted].

Orthogonal Encoder-Decoder Factorization for Unsupervised Feature Selection

M. Mozafari, **S. A. Seyedi**, R. Pirmohamadiani, and F. Akhlaghian. *Information Sciences*, 2024.

Multi-Label Feature Selection with Global and Local Label Correlation

M. Faraji, S. A. Seyedi, F. Akhlaghian, and R. Mahmoodi.

Expert Systems with Applications, volume 246, 2024, pp. 123198.

Deep Asymmetric Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Graph Clustering

A. Hajiveiseh, S. A. Seyedi, and F. Akhlaghian.

Pattern Recognition, volume 148, 2024, pp. 110179.

2023 | Link Prediction by Adversarial Nonnegative Matrix Factorization

R. Mahmoodi, **S. A. Seyedi**, F. Akhlaghian, and A. Abdollahpouri.

Knowledge-based Systems, volume 280, 2023, pp. 110998.

Self-Supervised Semi-Supervised Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Data Clustering

J. Chavoshinejad, S. A. Seyedi, and F. Akhlaghian.

Pattern Recognition, volume 137, 2023, pp. 109282.

Adversarial Elastic Deep Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Matrix Completion

S. A. Seyedi, F. Akhlaghian, A. Lotfi, N. Salahian, and J. Chavoshinejad

Information Sciences, volume 621, 2023, pp. 562-579.

Deep Autoencoder-Like NMF with Contrastive Regularization and Feature Relationship Preservation

N. Salahian, F. Akhlaghian, S. A. Seyedi, and J. Chavoshinejad

Expert Systems with Applications, volume 214, 2023, pp. 119051.

2020 | Asymmetric Semi-Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Directed Graph Clustering

R. Abdollahi, S. A. Seyedi, and M. R. Noorimehr

IEEE International Conference on Computer and Knowledge Engineering (ICCKE), 2020, pp. 323-328.

2019 | Self-Paced Multi-Label Learning with Diversity

S. A. Seyedi, S. S. Ghodsi, F. Akhlaghian Tab, M. Jalili, and P. Moradi

Asian Conference on Machine Learning (ACML), 2019, pp. 790-805.

2018 Dynamic Graph-based Label Propagation for Density Peaks Clustering

S. A. Seyedi, A. Lotfi, P. Moradi, and N. N. Qader

Expert Systems with Applications, Volume 115, 2019, pp. 314-328.

2017 A Weakly-Supervised Factorization Method with Dynamic Graph Embedding

S. A. Seyedi, P. Moradi, and F. Akhlaghian Tab

IEEE Artificial Intelligence and Signal Processing Conference (AISP), 2017, pp. 213-218.

A Clustering-based Matrix Factorization Method to Improve the Accuracy of Recommendation Systems

Z. Shajarian, S. A. Seyedi, and P. Moradi

IEEE Iranian Conference on Electrical Engineering (ICEE), 2017, pp. 2241-2246.

2016 An Improved Density Peaks Method for Data Clustering

A. Lotfi, S. A. Seyedi, and P. Moradi

IEEE International Conference on Computer and Knowledge Engineering (ICCKE), 2016, pp. 263-268.

AMJAD SEYEDI 2

COMPUTER SKILLS

Operationg Systems Microsoft Windows and Linux (ubuntu, centOS, fedora, and RedHat distributions)

Word processing & Presentation Office suites and LTFX, Manim (animation engine for explanatory math videos)

Vector and raster softwares Adobe Illustrator, CorelDRAW, Inkscape, Adobe Photoshop, and GIMP

Development Tools Pycharm, Jupyter Notebook, Colab, Visual Studio, IntelliJ Idea, and Eclipse

Web design HTML, CSS, ASP.NET, and JavaScript

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

2019 – present **Python**, PyTorch, NumPy, and scikit-learn 2015 – 2020 **MATLAB**, linear algebra and visulaziation

2012 – 2015 JAVA, object-oriented software engineeing and web development

2009 – 2015 C++ C#, Software Ebgineering and Web development

2007 – 2009 Basic | Visual Basic, Software Engineering

66 REFERENCES

Fardin Akhlaghian, Associate Professor Department of Computer Engineering UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, SANANDAJ, IRAN

@ f.akhlaghian@uok.ac.ir

+98 918 873 8383

Alireza Abdollahpouri, Associate Professor Department of Computer Engineering UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, SANANDAJ, IRAN

@ abdollahpouri@uok.ac.ir

+98 918 877 0993

Parham Moradi, Associate Professor Department of Computer Engineering UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, SANANDAJ, IRAN

p.moradi@uok.ac.ir

+98 912 513 5478

Mahdi Jalili, Professor

School of Electrical and Computer Engineering RMIT UNIVERSITY, MELBOURNE, AUSTRALIA

@ mahdi.jalili@rmit.edu.au

+61 399 251 223

End of CV

AMJAD SEYEDI 3